# Graeme Oxley

Greater Sheffield Area



in linkedin.com/in/graemeoxley



oxley.graeme@googlemail.com



**%** 07833450471

# Summary

Quality minded Technical Test Manager with proven experience of project management and the development lifecycle. Working on numerous successfully implemented projects for Blue chip companies on high profile projects in the Telecoms, Banking and Financial services sectors. Effective management of acceptance/test teams on delivering multiple high quality large and BAU projects from requirements gathering to go live and support. Well versed and experienced in Waterfall, Agile and DevOps delivery models utilising cloud-based architectures and RPA.

# **Experience**



# Test Manager

Qualitest

May 2019 - Present (11 months +)



# 🔼 Test Manager

Equiniti

May 2016 - Apr 2019 (3 years)

May 2016 - Present Equiniti Digital: Test Manager

Reporting to the Head of QA & Testing; Technical Test Manager supporting multiple business units and products. Focused on automation frameworks and performance testing.

- Responsible for the Functional and Non-functional testing of multiple projects and products
- Overseeing Digital Transformation including:
- o Migration to cloud based services in Azure (IAAS/SAAS)
- o Creation of automated test suits executed as Azure pipelines tasks (CI/CD)
- o GIT source control for Infrastructure as code (IAC) and all project artefacts
- o Docker containerisation of Selenium grid for distributed test execution (Parallel Testing)
- o Collaboration tooling. Setting up MS Teams/Yammer/0365 Use of Azure DevOps
- o Work Classification and constraints identification and mitigation
- o Setting up KPI's and Dashboards in Power BI
- API Testing Restful & PDI
- Co-ordination of performance & penetration testing
- Project and capacity planning
- Test environment management
- Line management of project & BAU test teams, both onshore and offshore 12+ People
- Co-ordination with third party test tool suppliers (TFS/VSO)
- Definition and implementation of automation framework, methodologies (CUIT/Selenium)
- Working with programme/project managers, BA's, developers and environments team
- Management of risks and issues impacting testing and project delivery
- Providing regular reports/dashboards to programme/project management/stakeholders
- Customer UAT support
- Releases to existing customers and major on-boarding projects



### **Principal Non Functional Test Engineer**

Vocalink, a Mastercard company

Nov 2015 - Apr 2016 (6 months)

- Responsible for the Non Functional testing of multiple projects
- Effective planning and line management of the NFT Team
- Co-ordination with third party test tool suppliers
- Automation framework and methodology definition and implementation
- Working with program, project managers, analysis's, environments team
- Management of risks and issues impacting testing
- Reporting

### Test Manager

#### **HSBC**

Apr 2011 - Sep 2015 (4 years 6 months)

Test Manager for HSBC Global Payments Systems. Accountable for functional testing of all projects in a release.

- Owned Test Requirements specification, planning and management for all releases..
- Accountable for all functional testing activities for each release.
- Responsible for liaison and coordination of multiple third-party suppliers.
- Direct line management of multiple concurrent project test teams, both local and offshore, with responsibility for 15 staff.
- Managed production of project test documentation, status reports, project dashboards for communication with key stakeholders.
- Risk assessment, management and mitigation.
- Worked closely and built rapport with Program/Project Managers, BA's, Environments Team and thirdparties to drive on-time/on-budget/on-quality project goals, objectives and deliverables.



### **Test Manager**

# Capita

Jan 2009 - Apr 2011 (2 years 4 months)

Test Manager within the Life and Pensions team. Migrating legacy Pension administration Systems from Prudential and Co-op to a Capita administered centralised system.

- Line management of project test team 8+ People.
- Management of the delivery of testing of systems in accordance with requirements.
- Managing the production of test documentation, planning, execution and sign-off of testing.
- Identification of risks and issues affecting the planning, execution and sign-off of the project testing.
- Promotion continual professional development within team via regular Appraisals, objectives setting and training.

# Test Manager

#### Vodafone

Jun 2007 - Jan 2009 (1 year 8 months)

Acceptance Manager in the Multimedia Applications and Content Services (MACS) domain for Vodafone UK. Managing technical acceptance of multiple internal and external supplied and developed services and applications.

- Owned Test Requirements specification, planning and management.
- Accountable for all functional and non-functional testing activities.
- Responsible for liaison and coordination of multiple third-party suppliers.
- Running Onshore and Offshore Acceptance teams up to 7 people + 3rd parties.
- Vodafone Live! Service Acceptance/Sign Off project included:-
- Acceptance of Mobile TV Helix Streaming Servers.

- Managed acceptance testing of new VF Live Handsets and Clients including Nokia, Samsung, Sony Ericsson and Blackberry.
- Managed acceptance of Mobile Advertising Yahoo.
- Managed acceptance of MMS services.
- Managed acceptance Vodafone Voice Mail Services.
- Managed acceptance of Billing and enterprise solutions (M-Pay, MAF).
- Managed acceptance Mobile Widgets platform on handsets and VF Live.
- Managed acceptance post and pre-pay charging systems.
- Managed acceptance of on device portal.
- Member of Acceptance Team on "Make the Most of Now" VF Live upgrade.

# **Senior Systems Test Engineer**

#### **Panasonic**

Aug 1999 - Jun 2006 (6 years 11 months)

Senior System Test Engineer in Research and Development for Panasonic Mobile Communications Development of Europe (PMCDE).

- Creating and using test methodologies and environments for the latest features of the next generation of mobile phones.
- Testing standard 2G and 3G functions (Calls, SMS, UI).
- Test feature lead performing delegation of tasks and developing and appraising team members.
- Requirements Capture/Review.
- Bluetooth Testing.
- Video Streaming Testing.
- WAP Testing.
- Video Telephony Testing.
- 2G and 3G Protocol Testing.
- SIM Card Testing.
- Handsets worked on:- GD30, GD35, GD50, GD70, GD90, GD93P(GPRS), GD67, X70, X700 VS3,VS7(3G).

# Project R&D Engineer

### Schneider Electric

Jan 1996 - Aug 1999 (3 years 8 months)

Projects Engineer in the MV Switchgear R&D domain for Schneider Electric. Responsible for the specification, development and testing of digital electronic devices to automate the power network.

Developing power fault detection products and integration into the company's existing product range.

- Hardware/Software development/Testing
- SCADA Integration (Talus/Sprite)
- EMC Testing and certification.

# Commissioning Technician

#### **BNFL**

Sep 1994 - Sep 1995 (1 year 1 month)

Commissioning Technician on THORP for BNFL. Industrial work experience for a year as part of my degree course.

- Radiological instrument commissioning/calibration
- SCADA Integration (VME/PLC)

## Education



Manchester Met. University

Hons, Electrical/Electronic Engineering

**Rother Valley College** 

Engineering National Diploma, Computer Technology/Computer Systems Technology

# **Licenses & Certifications**

nterior Prince 2 Practitioner - APM Group

Issued Apr 2007 - Expires Apr 2012 PSR/214629

Chartered Engineer - Engineering Council 527072

macon UMTS - Signalling & Protocal Analysis (UTRAN and UE) - Inacon

man GPRS A Technical Perspective - Wray Castle

**Data over GSM Networks** - Wray Castle

**GSM Air Interface** - Wray Castle

**Linux TCP/IP Networking and Services** - Learning Tree

managing Buisness Projects - Cap Gemini

**ISEB Qualified** - Information Systems Examinations Board

**UMTS - Design Details and System Engineering** - Inacon

**C Programming** 

**Bluetooth** - Wray Castle

# **Skills**

Testing • System Testing • Integration • Software Quality Assurance • Telecommunications • Mobile Devices • Test Management • Defect Tracking • Test Strategy • Regression Testing